<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Natural Language Processing on kinow</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/tags/natural-language-processing.html</link><description>Recent content in Natural Language Processing on kinow</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Bruno P. Kinoshita All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 10:15:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kinoshita.eti.br/tags/natural-language-processing/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to remove the signature from e-mails with NLP?</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/06/14/how-to-remove-the-signature-from-e-mails-with-nlp.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/06/14/how-to-remove-the-signature-from-e-mails-with-nlp.html</guid><description>Some time ago I stumbled across EmailParser, a Python utility to remove e-mail signatures. Here&amp;rsquo;s a sample input e-mail from the project documentation.
Wendy – thanks for the intro! Moving you to bcc. Hi Vincent – nice to meet you over email. Apologize for the late reply, I was on PTO for a couple weeks and this is my first week back in office. As Wendy mentioned, I am leading an AR/VR taskforce at Foobar Retail Solutions.</description></item><item><title>Natural Language Processing and Natural Language Understanding</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/06/03/natural-language-processing-and-natural-language-understanding.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/06/03/natural-language-processing-and-natural-language-understanding.html</guid><description>I used Natural Language Processing (NLP) tools in a few projects in the past years. But only recently, while involved with a chatbot project, I noticed the term Natural Language Understanding (NLU).
NLU can be seen as a subfield of NLP. NLP englobes all techniques used for parsing text and extracting some knowledge about it. It could be finding out what are the common entities in the text, calculating the likelihood of a certain word being a preposition or a verb, sentiment analysis, or even spell checking sentences.</description></item><item><title>Using Google Natural Language API in an AWS Elastic Beanstalk application</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/03/15/using-google-natural-language-api-in-an-aws-elastic-beanstalk-application.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/03/15/using-google-natural-language-api-in-an-aws-elastic-beanstalk-application.html</guid><description>Besides providing an API for users and developers, Google also provides a series of (very well-written) client implementation, in several programming languages. That&amp;rsquo;s the case for Google Storage, Google Vision, and for Google Natural Language API&amp;rsquo;s.
I recently had to use the latter in a POC at work, and ran into an interesting issue with our AWS Elastic Beanstalk environment.
Google Language API requires that clients authenticate before sending requests. If you use their google-cloud-java, you can define the GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIALS.</description></item><item><title>Proposed logos for OpenNLP</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/01/15/proposed-logos-for-opennlp.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/01/15/proposed-logos-for-opennlp.html</guid><description>A couple of logos submitted to OPENNLP-6. Made with Inkscape, fonts from Google Fonts.</description></item></channel></rss>