<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming on kinow</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/tags/programming.html</link><description>Recent content in Programming on kinow</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Bruno P. Kinoshita All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 13:49:29 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kinoshita.eti.br/tags/programming/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Logo: Dev Multitask 100 videos</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2024/05/11/logo-dev-multitask-100-videos.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 01:33:52 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2024/05/11/logo-dev-multitask-100-videos.html</guid><description>I modified the DevMultitask channel logo for their 100th video: https://twitter.com/DevMultitask
Dev Multitask 100 videos The party effects are from another logo I designed for the Apache Software Foundation 20th anniversary.</description></item><item><title>Logo: Java Ring</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2024/04/28/logo-java-ring.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 22:36:52 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2024/04/28/logo-java-ring.html</guid><description>I created this logo sometime ago for the Java community of a friend: https://twitter.com/java_ring
Java Ring logo Acquired a license for the logo, got a copy of Duke in SVG, and some quick Inkscape-ing to slice paths and re-order them.</description></item><item><title>Coverage report for a GitHub private repository with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2023/05/29/coverage-report-for-a-github-private-repository-with-github-actions.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 20:36:52 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2023/05/29/coverage-report-for-a-github-private-repository-with-github-actions.html</guid><description>Normally when you add test coverage to a GitHub repository, the reporting part boils down to a simple call to some API that will post to a third-party external service like Coveralls or Codecov. Many are already on the GitHub Actions Market Place and a few lines of YAML are enough.
A Codecov coverage report We had to report the test coverage of a private GitHub repository of a project I am working on at the moment, that could not have integration with other services besides GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Cyclic Workflows with Cylc and StackStorm</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2021/10/01/cyclic-workflows-with-cylc-and-stackstorm.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2021/10/01/cyclic-workflows-with-cylc-and-stackstorm.html</guid><description>I am aware of only two workflow managers that support cyclic workflows. Cylc and StackStorm. I won&amp;rsquo;t enter into details about these two tools, but I must note that I worked on Cylc during my employment with NIWA, in New Zealand.
In this post I will only show a very simple workflow called five first using Cylc, and then the same workflow with StackStorm.
Cylc First let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the source code of this workflow with Cylc 8 and plot it.</description></item><item><title>Using Lumino with Vue</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2020/03/28/using-lumino-with-vue.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2020/03/28/using-lumino-with-vue.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/jupyterlab/lumino">Lumino&lt;/a> is the engine that powers the GUI of
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jupyterlab/jupyterlab/">JupyterLab&lt;/a>. It used to be called Phosphor JS,
but some time ago there was a misunderstanding and the author gave up maintaining it.
Then JupyterLab decided to fork it under this new name.&lt;/p>



&lt;figure class="feature">

 &lt;img
 src='https://kinoshita.eti.br/assets/posts/2020-03-28-using-lumino-with-vue/demo.gif'
 alt=''
 title=''
 style=''
 width=''
 height=''
 />
 &lt;figcaption>&lt;/figcaption>

&lt;/figure>


&lt;p>The documentation is still lacking, but it works as expected, and there is already a
community supporting it. We decided to use it in &lt;a href="https://github.com/cylc/cylc-ui">Cylc UI&lt;/a>
to have tabbed panels like JupyterLab.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/kinow/vue-lumino">This project&lt;/a> contains the part of the code of
Cylc UI that integrated Lumino and Vue. It was a suggestion from one of the maintainers
of JupyterLab, that got involved in an issue of Cylc UI. You can find this project linked
too in the Lumino project &lt;code>README&lt;/code> file.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Experimenting with Vuejs and Cytoscape</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2019/11/19/experimenting-with-vuejs-and-cytoscape.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2019/11/19/experimenting-with-vuejs-and-cytoscape.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The project I work on at work had a GUI interface with Python and PyGTK, which is now being
ported to the web. We have adopted Vuejs as the JS framework, and have been building the
components required for our UI over the past months. The project is hosted
&lt;a href="https://github.com/cylc/cylc-ui">on GitHub&lt;/a> licensed under GPLv3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Cylc 7, an important visualization was the workflow graph. The screenshot below is from
the design sketches done by another contributor from the UK, showing how it should look in
Cylc 8.&lt;/p>



&lt;figure class="feature">

 &lt;img
 src='https://kinoshita.eti.br/assets/posts/2019-11-19-experimenting-with-vuejs-and-cytoscape/cylc8-sketch.png'
 alt=''
 title=''
 style=''
 width=''
 height=''
 />
 &lt;figcaption>&lt;/figcaption>

&lt;/figure>


&lt;p>The first library we decided to try is Cytoscape, a well-known graph library, with use cases
in research, corporate, and other fields. One limitation of Cytoscape is that the way it renders
the graph nodes is limited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Limited, meaning that you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to easily add HTML, images, SVG, animation, etc. Though
not impossible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generating diagrams from a SQlite database with Python</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2019/07/28/generating-diagrams-from-a-sqlite-database-with-python.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2019/07/28/generating-diagrams-from-a-sqlite-database-with-python.html</guid><description>&lt;figure class="feature">

 &lt;img
 src='https://kinoshita.eti.br/assets/posts/2019-07-28-generating-diagrams-from-a-sqlite-database-with-python/Amiga.png'
 alt='A 1984 Apple Macintosh drawing'
 title='A 1984 Apple Macintosh drawing'
 style='float: left; width: 30%;'
 width=''
 height=''
 />
 &lt;figcaption>A 1984 Apple Macintosh drawing&lt;/figcaption>

&lt;/figure>


&lt;p>There are tools out there that can be used to reverse engineer databases and generate diagrams. These tools
normally are GUI based. But &lt;a href="https://github.com/cylc/cylc-doc/pull/29">I needed&lt;/a> one that could be used in a
project build to generate a simple diagram for documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A tool in Python would be ideal, as that is the language the project I was working on was written in. After
searching in DuckDuckGo and PYPI, I found &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/ERAlchemy/">ERAlchemy&lt;/a> that
seemed to have the features I needed - kinda.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A look at the first implementation of GraphQL in Cylc</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2019/05/17/a-look-at-the-first-implementation-of-graphql-in-cylc.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2019/05/17/a-look-at-the-first-implementation-of-graphql-in-cylc.html</guid><description>&lt;figure class="feature">

 &lt;img
 src='https://kinoshita.eti.br/assets/posts/2019-05-17-a-look-at-the-first-implementation-of-graphql-in-cylc/fancy-hands2.png'
 alt=''
 title=''
 style='float: right; width: 40%;'
 width=''
 height=''
 />
 &lt;figcaption>&lt;/figcaption>

&lt;/figure>


&lt;p>For Cylc 8 we are adding an initial implementation of GraphQL, to replace the previous REST API.
Besides the technologies in the API&amp;rsquo;s, another difference is that for the REST API, its main
consumer was a PyGTK GUI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new GraphQL API, on the other hand, will be used mainly by a Vue.js Web application. So a
few things need to be done in a different way due to the jump from Desktop GUI to Web GUI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running fuzzers to find bugs</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2019/04/07/running-fuzzers-to-find-bugs.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2019/04/07/running-fuzzers-to-find-bugs.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Fuzzifying is a technique used in automated tests to find bugs in programs with unexpected data. fuzzer is the name given to the program used for running these tests. Some fuzzers also generate random data used for the tests.&lt;/p>



&lt;figure class="feature">

 &lt;img
 src='https://kinoshita.eti.br/assets/posts/2019-04-07-running-fuzzers-to-find-bugs/stink-bug-smaller.png'
 alt=''
 title=''
 style=''
 width=''
 height=''
 />
 &lt;figcaption>&lt;/figcaption>

&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>PyZMQ Basics - Part 1</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2019/03/30/pyzmq-basics-part-1.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2019/03/30/pyzmq-basics-part-1.html</guid><description>&lt;a href="https://www.deviantart.com/kinow/art/Old-man-1-657521623" style="float: left;">



&lt;figure class="feature">

 &lt;img
 src='https://kinoshita.eti.br/assets/posts/2019-03-30-pyzmq-basics-part-1/old-man-1.png'
 alt=''
 title=''
 style=''
 width=''
 height=''
 />
 &lt;figcaption>&lt;/figcaption>

&lt;/figure>


&lt;p>I am working &lt;a href="https://cylc.github.io">on a project&lt;/a> that is adopting &lt;a href="http://zeromq.org/">ZeroMQ&lt;/a>.
This post series is for self understanding of PyZMQ, a ZeroMQ
&lt;a href="https://github.com/zeromq/libzmq">&lt;code>libzmq&lt;/code>&lt;/a> binding for Python.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-zeromq">What is ZeroMQ?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ZeroMQ (or 0MQ, or ØMQ) is an Open Source library that provides building blocks for
communication in distributed applications. The communication can be between the threads
of a process, between process (inter-process), or via network protocols such as
TCP and UDP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is optimized for performance, and has been used in many applications, giving users
a solid foundation to be used in their projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running Cylc tasks on PBS Torque with Docker</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2018/12/22/running-cylc-tasks-on-pbs-torque-with-docker.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2018/12/22/running-cylc-tasks-on-pbs-torque-with-docker.html</guid><description>&lt;p>A few days ago I saw &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/cylc/dP2I1Gxqi20">a post&lt;/a> at the
Cylc Google Group, about file permissions for files generated by Cylc. The post was related to
content created by Cylc, but in an environment with PBS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For context, Cylc is an Open Source meta-scheduler, written in Python, that allows you to
define cycle points with dependencies. These cycle points can be simple incremental integer
numbers, or ISO8601 periods or points (e.g. run every 5 minutes, from 10 days ago until the
next year). Cylc takes care to create an execution schedule for you, and delegate that to a
system that runs your workflow. I work full time on this amazing Open Source tool!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such system could be the local computer in background, batch systems such as &lt;code>at&lt;/code>, or PBS.
PBS was created for NASA, to manage executing jobs taking into consideration cluster resources,
and also using queues, priorities, and other features useful for HPC programming. Later PBS
was acquired by Altair, an Open Source version OpenPBS was created, and later abandoned. And
there is another fork called PBS Torque. I first encountered PBS at the São Paulo
University, in Brazil, where they had a &lt;a href="http://www.usp.br/hpc/puma.php">PBS Torque cluster&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="running-pbs-torque-with-docker">Running PBS Torque with Docker&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Even though I have access to an environment with Cylc and with PBS, I decided to give it a try
and see how hard it would be to reproduce it with Docker. One thing that I like about this
approach is the possibility to share the work with others online. I believe it improves
communication, agility, and can be useful for posterity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A couple of class diagrams of JupyterHub</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2018/10/06/a-couple-of-class-diagrams-of-jupyterhub.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2018/10/06/a-couple-of-class-diagrams-of-jupyterhub.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Started on a new project last Monday. One of the tasks in this project involves a new design
for the Web layer. And as the application is quite similar to &lt;a href="https://jupyterhub.readthedocs.io/">JupyterHub&lt;/a>,
we are all learning more about its internal API and general system design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post contains only two class diagrams created with PyCharm. One is actually a SQLAlchemy
ORM diagram, below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p style='text-align: center;'>
&lt;a href="https://kinoshita.eti.br/assets/posts{{page.path | remove: ".md" | remove: "_posts" }}/jupyterhub-sqlalchemy-graph.png">



&lt;figure class="feature">

 &lt;img
 src='https://kinoshita.eti.br/assets/posts/2018-10-06-a-couple-of-class-diagrams-of-jupyterhub/jupyterhub-sqlalchemy-graph.png'
 alt=''
 title=''
 style='display: inline; width: 100%;'
 width=''
 height=''
 />
 &lt;figcaption>&lt;/figcaption>

&lt;/figure>


&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cylc Scheduler Internals - Part 3</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2018/08/18/cylc-scheduler-internals-part-3.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2018/08/18/cylc-scheduler-internals-part-3.html</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the part 3, in a series of posts about &lt;a href="https://cylc.github.io/cylc">Cylc&lt;/a>
internals. The [part 1]({% post_url 2018-07-14-cylc-scheduler-internals-part-1 %})
had the beginning of the workflow. [part 2]({% post_url 2018-07-27-cylc-scheduler-internals-part-2 %})
documented from the moment the method &lt;code>configure()&lt;/code> is called. This post will
continue right after the &lt;code>continue()&lt;/code> method returns, going on with the next method: &lt;code>run()&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p style='text-align: center;'>
&lt;a href="https://kinoshita.eti.br/assets/posts{{page.path | remove: ".md" | remove: "_posts" }}/cylc-scheduler_run.png">



&lt;figure class="feature">

 &lt;img
 src='https://kinoshita.eti.br/assets/posts/2018-08-18-cylc-scheduler-internals-part-3/cylc-scheduler_run.png'
 alt=''
 title=''
 style='display: inline; width: 100%;'
 width=''
 height=''
 />
 &lt;figcaption>&lt;/figcaption>

&lt;/figure>


&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What happens when you upload a Turtle file in Apache Jena Fuseki</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2018/05/27/what-happens-when-you-upload-a-turtle-file-in-apache-jena-fuseki.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2018/05/27/what-happens-when-you-upload-a-turtle-file-in-apache-jena-fuseki.html</guid><description>I am working on an issue for Skosmos that involves preparing some Turtle files and uploading them using Apache Jena Fuseki&amp;rsquo;s web interface.
The issue is now pending feedback, which gives me a moment to have fun with something else. So I decided to dig down the rabbit hole and start learning more about certain parts of the Apache Jena code base.
This post will be useful to myself in the future, as a note-taking in a series, so that I remember how things work - you never know right?</description></item><item><title>Exif Odd Offsets</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/12/25/exif-odd-offsets.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/12/25/exif-odd-offsets.html</guid><description>A file format like JPEG may contain metadata in JFIF, Exif, or a vendor proprietary format. The Exif format is based - or uses parts of - on the TIFF format.
Within an Exif metadata block, you should see directories, with several entries. The entries have fields like description, value, and also an offset. The offset indicates the offset to the next entry.
The Exif specification defines that implementers must make sure to keep the offset an even number, within 4 bytes.</description></item><item><title>Remember to synchronize when iterating streams from a synchronized Collection</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/12/03/remember-to-synchronize-when-iterating-streams-from-a-synchronized-collection.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/12/03/remember-to-synchronize-when-iterating-streams-from-a-synchronized-collection.html</guid><description>When iterating collections created via Collections.synchronizedList for instance, you are required to obtain a lock on the actual list before doing so. So you normally end up with code similar to:
List list = Collections.synchronizedList(new ArrayList()); synchronized (list) { Iterator i = list.iterator(); // Must be in synchronized block while (i.hasNext()) foo(i.next()); } This requirement is documented in the javadocs.
Since lambdas and streams are being more widely used, it is important to remind that when iterating via a stream we also need to obtain a lock on the synchronized collection created.</description></item><item><title>Watch out for Locales when using NumberFormat with currencies</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/12/02/watch-out-for-locales-when-using-numberformat-with-currencies.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/12/02/watch-out-for-locales-when-using-numberformat-with-currencies.html</guid><description>In Java you have the NumberFormatException to help you formatting and parsing numbers for any locale. Said that, here&amp;rsquo;s some code.
BigDecimal negative = new BigDecimal(&amp;#34;-1234.56&amp;#34;); DecimalFormat nf = (DecimalFormat) NumberFormat.getCurrencyInstance(Locale.UK); String formattedNegative = nf.format(negative); System.out.println(formattedNegative); The output for this code is -£1,234.56. That&amp;rsquo;s expected, as the locale is set to UK, so the currency symbol used is for British Pounds. And as the number is negative, you get that minus sign as a prefix.</description></item><item><title>What Are Identification Keys</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/12/01/what-are-identification-keys.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/12/01/what-are-identification-keys.html</guid><description>In biology, an identification key is a printed or computer-aided device that aids the identification of biological entities, such as plants, animals, fossils, microorganisms, and pollen grains. Identification keys are also used in many other scientific and technical fields to identify various kinds of entities, such as diseases, soil types, minerals, or archaeological and anthropological artifacts
When you work writing software, it is common that at one point or another of the product development you will work with a SME, or subject-matter expert.</description></item><item><title>Using formatter exclusions with Eclipse</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/11/06/using-formatter-exclusions-with-eclipse.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/11/06/using-formatter-exclusions-with-eclipse.html</guid><description>Sometimes when you are formatting your code in Eclipse, you may want to prevent some parts of the code from being formatted. Especially when using Java 8 lambdas and optionals.
Here&amp;rsquo;s some code before being formatted by Eclipse&amp;rsquo;s default formatter rules.
Code adapted from: blog post Java d&amp;rsquo;eau ‐ Java 8: Streams in Hibernate and Beyond
session.createQuery(&amp;#34;SELECT h FROM Hare h&amp;#34;, Hare.class) .stream() .filter(h -&amp;gt; h.getId() == 1) .map(Hare::getName) .forEach(System.out::println); Then after formatting.</description></item><item><title>Quickly Verifying jar Signatures For ASF Releases</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/10/14/quickly-verifying-jar-signatures-for-asf-releases.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/10/14/quickly-verifying-jar-signatures-for-asf-releases.html</guid><description>The release process within the Apache Software Foundation includes a series of steps. Amongst these steps is the voting process. In Apache Commons, the release instructions includes a note on artefact signatures.
During the course of the VOTE, make sure that one or more of the reviewers have verified the signatures and hash files included with the release artifacts. If no one specifically mentions having done that during the VOTE, ask on the dev list and make sure someone does this before you proceed with the release.</description></item></channel></rss>