<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on kinow</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/tags/articles.html</link><description>Recent content in Articles on kinow</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Bruno P. Kinoshita All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 11:03:03 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kinoshita.eti.br/tags/articles/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Paper: Patterns for Introducing a Superclass for Test Classes</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2012/09/25/paper-patterns-for-introducing-a-superclass-for-test-classes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2012/09/25/paper-patterns-for-introducing-a-superclass-for-test-classes.html</guid><description>Few days ago we had SugarLoafPlop 2012 in Natal - RN
It is a conference on pattern languages of programming. About six months ago I saw a tweet by Eduardo Guerra asking if anyone had some cases where certain patterns were applied. It was a big coincidence, since I was working on Apache Commons Functor and some Jenkins plugins, both projects with cases that could be used in his paper.</description></item><item><title>Faça seus Testes Falarem TAP (Make your Tests Speak TAP) article published in MundoJ, issue 47, March/April 2011</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2011/05/23/fa%C3%A7a-seus-testes-falarem-tap-make-your-tests-speak-tap-article-published-in-mundoj-issue-47-march/april-2011.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2011/05/23/fa%C3%A7a-seus-testes-falarem-tap-make-your-tests-speak-tap-article-published-in-mundoj-issue-47-march/april-2011.html</guid><description>This is my first article for a Brazilian magazine! :-D It was published in this month&amp;rsquo;s issue of MundoJ magazine (previously called MundoJava).
In this article Cesar Fernandes de Almeida, Anderson dos Santos and I discuss how to make your Java tests output TAP (Test Anything Protocol) Streams. This test protocol has been used by Perl developers since Perl&amp;rsquo;s first version (1983~) but hasn&amp;rsquo;t been used by many Java developers yet, unfortunately.</description></item><item><title>TestLink and Hudson (now Jenkins) short tutorial in Automated Software Testing Magazine, issue March 2011</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2011/03/22/testlink-and-hudson-now-jenkins-short-tutorial-in-automated-software-testing-magazine-issue-march-2011.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2011/03/22/testlink-and-hudson-now-jenkins-short-tutorial-in-automated-software-testing-magazine-issue-march-2011.html</guid><description>Hi there, a new article about TestLink and Hudson (now Jenkins) was published, now in Automated Software Testing Magazine, issue March 2011. In this article you will find a short tutorial to set up a TestNG test and a simple Job to execute your automated tests. Now we are writing a docbook document to explain with more details how the plug-in works and how you can play with it. We are also working in more samples, translation and video demos.</description></item><item><title>Article about TestLink and Hudson integration published</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2010/12/10/article-about-testlink-and-hudson-integration-published.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2010/12/10/article-about-testlink-and-hudson-integration-published.html</guid><description>Since September I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project to integrate TestLink and Hudson. The project consists basically in a Hudson Plug-in that uses TestLink Java API to retrieve information of Automated Test Cases created in TestLink. You can read more about the plug-in in the following address: http://wiki.hudson-ci.org/display/HUDSON/TestLink+Plugin.
I wrote an article in conjunction with Anderson dos Santos about this Plug-in. The article was published by Testing Experience in its December issue.</description></item><item><title>Article about metrics and code analysis published</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2010/09/03/article-about-metrics-and-code-analysis-published.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2010/09/03/article-about-metrics-and-code-analysis-published.html</guid><description>I wrote an article about a quality analysis job done for a client of Sysmap Solutions and it was published by TestingExperience Magazine on its issue of September, number 11.
You can check the full article in TestingExperience site. It is available in PDF format for members, the registration if free though.
Happy reading.</description></item></channel></rss>