<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bioinformatics on kinow</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/tags/bioinformatics.html</link><description>Recent content in Bioinformatics on kinow</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Bruno P. Kinoshita All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 20:30:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kinoshita.eti.br/tags/bioinformatics/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Strings transliteration in Java with Apache Commons Lang</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2014/08/09/strings-transliteration-in-java-with-apache-commons-lang.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2014/08/09/strings-transliteration-in-java-with-apache-commons-lang.html</guid><description>Rosalind is a website with a curated set of exercices for bioinformatics, organized hierarchily. In some of these examples you are required to replace characters (nucleotides) by other characters. It is a rather common task for developers, like when you need to replace special characters in user&amp;rsquo;s names.
There are different ways of describing it, such as translate, replace, or transliterate. The latter being my favorite definition.
In Python I know that there are several different ways of transliterating strings [1][2].</description></item><item><title>Bioinformatics tools: Stacks</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2012/09/25/bioinformatics-tools-stacks.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2012/09/25/bioinformatics-tools-stacks.html</guid><description>&lt;p>It is the first post about &lt;strong>bioinformatics tools&lt;/strong>, but I will try to post more about other tools such
as MrBayes, Structure, maybe some next generation sequencing tools too, and Bioperl, Biojava, and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I am more a computer geek, rather than a bioinformatics one, I will focus on requirements for running these tools
on clusters and the requirements to install them on your machine. The instructions require that you have an
intermediary knowledge on *nix OS and sometimes a bit of programming experience.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I will be using tutorials available on the Internet and hosting my code in &lt;a href="http://www.github.com/kinow" alt="GitHub kinow" title="GitHub kinow">GitHub/kinow&lt;/a>. Hammer time!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>