<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aws on kinow</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/tags/aws.html</link><description>Recent content in Aws on kinow</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Bruno P. Kinoshita All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:03:25 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kinoshita.eti.br/tags/aws/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Google Natural Language API in an AWS Elastic Beanstalk application</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/03/15/using-google-natural-language-api-in-an-aws-elastic-beanstalk-application.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/03/15/using-google-natural-language-api-in-an-aws-elastic-beanstalk-application.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Besides providing an API for users and developers, Google also provides a series of
(very well-written) client implementation, in several programming languages. That&amp;rsquo;s the
case for Google Storage, Google Vision, and for Google Natural Language API&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recently had to use the latter in a POC at work, and ran into an interesting issue with
our AWS Elastic Beanstalk environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Google Language API requires that clients authenticate before sending requests. If you use their &lt;a href="https://github.com/GoogleCloudPlatform/google-cloud-java">google-cloud-java&lt;/a>, you can define the GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIALS. This environment variable must point to a JSON file with the Google Language API credentials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using AWS MFA without a mobile phone</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/02/28/using-aws-mfa-without-a-mobile-phone.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2017/02/28/using-aws-mfa-without-a-mobile-phone.html</guid><description>&lt;p>If you use AWS, the chances are that you use MFA - Multi-factor Authentication - to authenticate.
I don&amp;rsquo;t like to install apps in my mobile phone, unless I need to, so having bought a new phone
recently, I decided to find a replacement for Google Authenticator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several command line utilities, browser extensions, libraries, and tools (free and paid)
that implement the TOTP - time-based one-time password -, the standard
&lt;a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/id_credentials_mfa_enable_virtual.html">required by Amazon&lt;/a>
for MFA authentication.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using the AWS API with Python</title><link>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2016/10/04/using-the-aws-api-with-python.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kinoshita.eti.br/2016/10/04/using-the-aws-api-with-python.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Amazon Web Services provides a series of cloud services. When you access the web interface, most - if not all - of the actions you do there are actually translated into API calls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They also provide SDK&amp;rsquo;s in several programming languages. With these SDK&amp;rsquo;s you are able to call the same API used by the web interface. Python has &lt;a href="https://github.com/boto/boto3">boto&lt;/a> (or boto3) which lets you to automate several tasks in AWS.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>